<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- Command Line Interface -->
<dr tags="base-functionality" status="done">
  <title>
    Command Line Interface
  </title>
  <description>
    Autoscrum will support a command line tool, which will be the primary
    interface for the user to interact with Autoscrum.
  </description>

  <children>
    <dr>
      <title>
	Naming of the Autoscrum Master
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will allow the team the ability to name the Autoscrum
	Master.	
      </description>
    </dr>
    <dr tags="base-functionality">
      <title>
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will be able to handle two or more requests from different
	users simultaneously.
      </description>
    </dr>
    <dr>
      <title>
	Interactive Shell
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will support an interactive shell as part of the command
	line tool.
      </description>
    </dr>
    <dr>
      <title>
	Command Auto Completion
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will support command line auto-completion.
      </description>
    </dr>
    <dr>
      <title>
	Search Features
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will support advanced search features on the command line.
      </description>
      <children>
	<dr>
	  <title>
	    Keyword Searches
	  </title>
	  <description>
	    Autoscrum Search facilities will support keyword searches with
	    the boolean operators 'and' and 'or'. Keyword search will be the
	    default behavior of the search engine.
	  </description>
	  <children>
	    <dr>
	      <title>
		Multiple Keyword Searches
	      </title>
	      <description>
		When multiple keywords are specified in the search, the default
		value will be to locate search results which contain all of the
		keywords, in any particular order. 
	      </description>
	    </dr>
	    <dr>
	      <title>
		Keyword Search Case Sensitivity
	      </title>
	      <description>
		If the keywords contain only lowercase letters, Autoscrum
		will ignore case. Otherwise, searches will be case sensitive.
	      </description>
	    </dr>
	  </children>
	</dr>
	<dr>
	  <title>
	    Regex Searching
	  </title>
	  <description>
	    Autoscrum will support regular expression (BRE, POSIX.2) based
	    search features.
	  </description>
	  <children>
	    <dr>
	      <title>
		Configuration - Regex Searching
	      </title>
	      <description>
		Autoscrum will support configuration to enable or disable
		regular expression based searches.
	      </description>
	    </dr>
	    <dr>
	      <title>
		Regex Format
	      </title>
	      <description>
		Autoscrum will distinguish regex based searches from keyword
		based searches by the format `re/regex/', where `regex' is a
		POSIX.2 compliant BRE regex.
	      </description>
	    </dr>
	  </children>
	</dr>
      </children>
    </dr>
    <dr tags="base-functionality">
      <title>
	Command - Checkout
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will support a "checkout" command which will set one
	particular Scrum Object to be "active," meaning that any "update"
	commands won't need to be run with the fully qualified name of the
	Scrum Object.
      </description>
    </dr>
    <dr>
      <title>
	Command - List
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will have a "list" command, which lists the Scrum Objects
	that appear under the current (checked out) Object.
      </description>
    </dr>
    <dr tags="base-functionality">
      <title>
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will support a filesystem-like naming scheme to specify fully
	qualified names of Scrum Objects. Shown below is the format used.
	/project/
	|---epics/
	|---|---stories/
	|-------|---tasks/
	|-------|---issues/
      </description>
    </dr>
    <dr tags="base-functionality">
      <title>
	Error Handling
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will support a dedicated Error handling module, whose only
	purpose will be to enforce graceful and verbose error handling.
      </description>
      <children>
	<dr tags="base-functionality">
	  <title>
	  </title>
	  <description>
	    Autoscrum will generate an error message in the case that the user
	    issues a command to update a Scrum Object without specifying a fully
	    qualified name and there is no currently checked out Scrum Object.
	  </description>
	</dr>
      </children>
    </dr>
    <dr tags="base-functionality">
      <title>
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will support a configuration module, containing key/value
	pairs, which can be modified by the user. The purpose of this module
	will be to allow the user to tune their experience for performance
	and behavior, to provide a unique experience optimized for their own
	workflow.
      </description>
    </dr>

    <!-- Login -->
    <dr tags="base-functionality">
      <title>
	User Login and Logout
      </title>
      <description>
	Autoscrum will require users log in to use resources and services
	provided by Autoscrum.
      </description>

      <children>
	<dr>
	  <title>
	  </title>
	  <description>
	    Autoscrum will support integration with preexisting user
	    information systems, such as openssl-passwd or LDAP.
	  </description>
	</dr>
	<dr>
	  <title>
	  </title>
	  <description>
	    Autoscrum will allow configuration of login/session behavior. This
	    configuration will be accessible only to the owner of the Autoscrum
	    executable.
	  </description>
	</dr>
	<dr>
	  <title>
	    Usernames in Unicode
	  </title>
	  <description>
	    Autoscrum users' registered Usernames will be stored in UTF-8,
	    allowing characters not part of ASCII to appear in usernames.
	  </description>
	</dr>

	<!-- Session -->
	<dr tags="base-functionality">
	  <title>
	    Login Sessions
	  </title>
	  <description>
	    Autoscrum will support temporary "sessions"--a period of time
	    where the user will not be asked to reauthenticate when they
	    attempt a query to Autoscrum's resources or services.
	  </description>
	  <children>
	    <dr>
	      <title>
		Session Length
	      </title>
	      <description>
		Autoscrum will support configuration of the length of time for
		which a valid session may exist, accessible only to the owner
		of the Autoscrum executable.
	      </description>
	    </dr>

	    <!-- Issues as Scrum Objects -->
	    <dr>
	      <title>
		Issues as Scrum Objects
	      </title>
	      <description>
		Autoscrum will support issues as objects for tracking the
		history of defects or problems with a project, as well as their
		resolution.
	      </description>
	      <children>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Issue Traceability
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    All issues must trace to a story in the project backlog.
		    After an issue has been submitted, it is placed in a
		    separate "unassigned issues" backlog, where it will
		    remain until the Project Owner associates it with a
		    story and assigns it to a Developer.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Votes for Issues
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support votes for Issues. Votes will
		    increase the priority of the issue, moving it up in the
		    backlog. Each registered Autoscrum user may vote only
		    once for an issue, and all votes are created equal.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support mirroring of issues submitted to any VCS
		    (Versioning Control System) Hosting Service.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for submitting issues by
		    any recognized Autoscrum user.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for closing issues, for the
		    Project Owner and any Developer assigned to resolve the issue.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for responding to issues,
		    for the Project Owner and any Developer assigned to the issue.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for assigning issues to
		    members of the Development Team, for the Project Owner.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Watchers for Issues
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support "watchers" for issues. Watchers
		    will be sent an email each time an update is made.
		  </description>
		</dr>
	      </children>
	    </dr>

	    <!-- Tasks as Scrum Objects -->
	    <dr tags="base-functionality">
	      <title>
		Tasks as Scrum Objects
	      </title>
	      <description>
		Autoscrum will support tasks as a means for updating progress
		towards completing stories.
	      </description>
	      <children>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Votes for Tasks
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support votes for Tasks. Votes will
		    increase the priority of the task, moving it up in the
		    backlog. Each registered Autoscrum user may vote only
		    once for an task, and all votes are created equal.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Watchers for Tasks
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support "watchers" for tasks. Watchers
		    will be sent an email each time an update is made.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for creating tasks for
		    stories, for the Developer who was given the story to complete.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for updating tasks, for the
		    Developer who was assigned the task.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface deleting tasks, for the
		    Developer who was given the story to complete.
		  </description>
		</dr>
	      </children>
	    </dr>

	    <!-- Stories as Scrum Objects -->
	    <dr tags="base-functionality">
	      <title>
		Stories as Scrum Objects
	      </title>
	      <description>
		<!-- TODO: Add reference to the Scrum Guide in the glossary -->
		Autoscrum will recognize Stories as Scrum Objects, according to
		The Scrum Guide.
	      </description>
	      <children>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Votes for Stories
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support votes for Stories. Votes will
		    increase the priority of the story, moving it up in the
		    backlog. Each registered Autoscrum user may vote only
		    once for an story, and all votes are created equal.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Watchers for Stories
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support "watchers" for stories. Watchers
		    will be sent an email each time an update is made.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for creating stories, for
		    the Project Owner.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for updating stories, for
		    the Project Owner and the Developer given the story to
		    complete.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for deleting stories, for
		    the Project Owner.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support "tags" for stories. Tags are static
		    references which are used to categorize and prioritize stories.
		  </description>
		</dr>
	      </children>
	    </dr>

	    <!-- Backlogs as Scrum Objects -->
	    <dr tags="base-functionality">
	      <title>
		Backlogs as Scrum Objects
	      </title>
	      <description>
		Autoscrum will maintain a backlog containing stories.
	      </description>
	      <children>
		<!-- Requirements that handle the user interface for the Backlog
		     object. -->
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support both automatic and manual backlog
		    maintenance.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support automatic story prioritization in the
		    backlog based on tags. Autoscrum will take as input an XML
		    hierarchy of tag priority. For the example below, assume that
		    tag1 is the parent of tag2, which is the parent of tag3 and
		    tag4, and tag3 and tag4 are siblings.
		    {
		    Story: Example story
		    Tags: tag1, tag3, tag4
		    Priority: f(l(tag1), l(tag3), l(tag4))
		    }
		    In the example, f() is a function which returns the total
		    priority of the story and l() is a function which returns the
		    level of the tag (i.e. l(tag1) = 0, l(tag3) = 2, etc).
		  </description>
		</dr>
	      </children>
	    </dr>

	    <!-- Epics as Scrum Objects -->
	    <dr tags="base-functionality">
	      <title>
		Epics as Scrum Objects
	      </title>
	      <description>
		Autoscrum will support "Epics." Epics are user defined periods
		of time which contain a number of sprints, related in some way
		to be associated together in a meaningful way.
	      </description>
	      <children>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Watchers for Epics
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support "watchers" for epics. Watchers
		    will be sent an email each time an update is made.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Creating Epics
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for creating Epics.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Updating Epics
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for updating Epics.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Deleting Epics
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for deleting Epics.
		  </description>
		</dr>
	      </children>
	    </dr>

	    <!-- Sprints as Scrum Objects -->
	    <dr tags="base-functionality">
	      <title>
		Sprints as Scrum Objects
	      </title>
	      <description>
		<!-- /* TODO: Add reference to the Scrum Guide. */ -->
		Autoscrum will support Sprints, according to the Scrum Guide.
	      </description>
	      <children>
		<!-- Requirements that handle the user interface for the Sprint
		     object. -->
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will allow configuration of sprint length.
		  </description>
		</dr>

		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will provide metrics to display the current
		    user's contribution to the sprint goal.
		  </description>
		  <children>
		    <!-- Requirements that handle the user interface for Sprint
			 Metrics and related objects. -->
		    <dr>
		      <title>
		      </title>
		      <description>
			Autoscrum will provide metrics to display the contribution of
			other users and the progress of the team. This printout will
			include to-do, in-progress, and completed stories.
		      </description>
		    </dr>
		    <dr>
		      <title>
		      </title>
		      <description>
			Autoscrum will support creation of graphs and other images
			in PNG format for any metrics which may be represented in
			this fashion.
		      </description>
		    </dr>
		  </children>
		</dr>

		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support creation of a Sprint Goal, according
		    to The Scrum Guide.
		  </description>
		  <children>
		    <!-- Requirements that handle the user interface for Sprint
			 Planning and related objects. -->
		    <dr tags="base-functionality">
		      <title>
		      </title>
		      <description>
			Autoscrum will support manual configuration of the sprint
			goal.
		      </description>
		    </dr>
		    <dr>
		      <title>
		      </title>
		      <description>
			Autoscrum will support automatic configuration of the sprint
			goal based on the developer bids, backlog, and Neural Network
			prediction of performance. The purpose of these inputs is to
			allow Autoscrum to assign the Sprint Goal to maximize the
			efficiency of the Development Team.
		      </description>
		    </dr>
		    <dr>
		      <title>
		      </title>
		      <description>
			Autoscrum will have a story bid submitting system which uses
			a modified Fibonacci sequence.
		      </description>
		    </dr>
		    <dr>
		      <title>
		      </title>
		      <description>
			Autoscrum will assign stories to developers after they have
			submitted their time bids for the upcoming sprint, if
			automatic sprint planning is enabled.
		      </description>
		    </dr>
		    <dr>
		      <title>
		      </title>
		      <description>
			Autoscrum will use a Neural Network to project team
			performance and to set the sprint goal.
		      </description>
		    </dr>

		    <dr>
		      <title>
		      </title>
		      <description>
			Autoscrum will use email as the primary mode of
			communication and Scrum event facilitation.
		      </description>
		      <children>
			<!-- Requirements that handle the user interface for Email and
			     related objects. -->
			<dr>
			  <title>
			  </title>
			  <description>
			    Autoscrum will sign its name at the end of every email to
			    the Development Team. This name is the name given to
			    Autoscrum by the Development Team.
			  </description>
			</dr>
			<dr>
			  <title>
			  </title>
			  <description>
			    Autoscrum will allow configuration for the content of the
			    email messages sent to the development team, for the
			    Project Owner and Scrum Master.
			  </description>
			</dr>
			<dr>
			  <title>
			  </title>
			  <description>
			    Autoscrum will support configuration for sending out an
			    email to all developers on the team at regular intervals,
			    if the Project Owner so desires, containing the progress
			    towards the sprint goal. This is how Autoscrum will
			    facilitate the "Daily Scrum."
			  </description>
			</dr>
			<dr>
			  <title>
			  </title>
			  <description>
			    Autoscrum will allow configuration of the time interval
			    that the "Daily Scrum" will occur.
			  </description>
			</dr>
			<dr>
			  <title>
			  </title>
			  <description>
			    Autoscrum will support configuration for sending an email
			    to the Development Team at the end of the sprint period, if
			    desired by the Project Owner. This email will facilitate
			    the "Sprint Review."
			  </description>
			</dr>
			<dr>
			  <title>
			  </title>
			  <description>
			    Autoscrum will allow configuration for sending the Sprint
			    Review to the Stakeholders, if desired by the Project
			    Owner.
			  </description>
			</dr>
			<dr>
			  <title>
			  </title>
			  <description>
			    Autoscrum will support configuration for sending an email
			    to the Development Team at the end of the sprint, if
			    desired by the Project Owner, in order to facilitate the
			    "Sprint Retrospective."
			  </description>
			</dr>
			<dr>
			  <title>
			  </title>
			  <description>
			    Autoscrum will support configuration for sending an email
			    to the Development Team containing the Sprint Goal, if so
			    desired by the Project Owner, when sprint planning is
			    complete. This may be configured to occur regardless of
			    whether automatic sprint planning is enabled.
			  </description>
			</dr>
		      </children>
		    </dr>
		  </children>
		</dr>
	      </children>
	    </dr>

	    <!-- Projects as Scrum Objects -->
	    <dr tags="base-functionality">
	      <title>
		Projects as Scrum Objects
	      </title>
	      <description>
		Autoscrum will support Projects as top level objects in the
		ecosystem.
	      </description>
	      <children>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		    Project Interface
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for creating Projects, for
		    any recognized Autoscrum user.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for updating Projects, for
		    the Project Owner.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will allow "private" projects--These projects will be
		    protected by a project-global password. In addition, recognized
		    Autoscrum users must be invited by the Project Owner to view
		    the project's resources.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will make all Projects "public" by default.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support an interface for deleting Projects, for
		    the Project Owner.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will have the capability to point to released
		    versions of the product.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will support Scrum roles for users, which will change
		    the user experience--this will affect user permissions and
		    responsibilities. Roles supported by Autoscrum include, but are
		    not limited to:
		    * Project Owner
		    * Scrum Master
		    * Developer
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr tags="base-functionality">
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will not allow a Project to exist without
		    administration by a registered Project Owner who is a
		    recognized Autoscrum user.
		  </description>
		</dr>
		<dr>
		  <title>
		  </title>
		  <description>
		    Autoscrum will be able to produce a comprehensive history of a
		    Project maintained by Autoscrum. The purpose of this is to
		    create a log which can be used (by an uninformed party, for
		    example) to follow the evolution of a product from inception.
		  </description>
		</dr>
	      </children>
	    </dr>

	  </children>
	</dr>
      </children>
    </dr>
  </children>
</dr>
